<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Datascience, tools and datasets</title>
    <link>https://scox3.github.io/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Datascience, tools and datasets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) Vladislav Borkus</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 10:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scox3.github.io/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dataset, MSK COVID-19 12 July 2021</title>
      <link>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-07-12-msk-covid-report-en/index-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-07-12-msk-covid-report-en/index-en/</guid>
      <description># This is a daily report on COVID-19 Moscow dataset. Code source for this report is here.
Cyclicity estimates ## Weekly diag. cyclicity coeffs:; 1.01; 0.86; 0.83; 1.09; 1.10; 1.09; 1.06 ## Weekly hosp. cyclicity coeffs:; 0.89; 1.04; 1.01; 1.04; 1.05; 1.05; 0.94 From cyclicity coeffs we may guess that hospitalizations are really 5 days lagged relative to newly diagnosted.
Trends ## [1] 266 Latest data table ## date new_diag new_diag_corr new_diag_week_av new_hosp new_hosp_corr ## 1: 2021-07-06 5498 6360.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataset compilation: Telegram and HTML parsing for COVID-19 epidemic data</title>
      <link>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-03-24-parse-telegram-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-03-24-parse-telegram-covid/</guid>
      <description>The data about hospitalizations with COVID-19 in Moscow are hard to find in public datasets. However these data are daily published in the specialized Telegram channel, so they can be parsed from there to be used in data analysis.
The first step is to download Telegram chat stream. That can be easily done with the desktop Telegram client so I will skip this step and assume that the necessary data, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strava tracks analysis in R</title>
      <link>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-03-22-gps-velo-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-03-22-gps-velo-en/</guid>
      <description>I like to run and ride a bike. I use Endomondo or Strava to write down GPS-tracks of my trainings and despite their commercial analytic capabilities are quite advanced as long as I know R it is compelling to use it to dissect my training data. Below I will tell how I do that.
Libraries 1. We will need special package XML2 to load data in the XLM formats, the package geosphere to calculate distances on Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface and the set of packages to draw tracks on Google Maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog with R and Hugo</title>
      <link>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-03-19-blog_with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-03-19-blog_with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is the great tool to build static web sites, i.e. sites with no backend database, just a plain HTML that is generated from a markup code. Such the site can be hosted on multiple platforms including Amazon and GitHub. The blog can be managed directly from RStudio. I tried to use Hugo for my blog and here is the log of this attempt with solutions to problems I encountered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rmarkdown nightmares (updated)</title>
      <link>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-03-18-rmarkdown-nightnames/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scox3.github.io/post/2021-03-18-rmarkdown-nightnames/</guid>
      <description>Setup Show whitespaces It would be clever to check the option &amp;ldquo;Options-&amp;gt;Code-&amp;gt;Display-&amp;gt;Show whitespace characters&amp;rdquo; in RStudio. Otherwise you will never know how many whitespaces you put at the end of a line, and then you may spend a lot of time figuring errors in paragraphs formatting. The rule of two spaces to end a paragraph is not the best feature of the markup language.
UTF8 If you use languages other than English to write your posts, do not forget to check &amp;ldquo;Options-&amp;gt;Code-&amp;gt;Saving-&amp;gt;Default&amp;rdquo; to set text encoding to UTF8, otherwise knitr will produce gibberish.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
